Preliminary Guide to the Josephine Humphreys Papers, 1946-1993 and undated RL.00590
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Josephine Humphreys papers
1946-1993 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Humphreys, Josephine
RL.00590
27.7 Linear Feet
11,900 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Josephine Humphreys Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift, 1992-1996.
Biographical Note
Author residing on Sullivan's Island (Charleston Co.), S.C.
Collection Overview
The collection documents Humphreys' professional life as an author. It contains correspondence between Humphreys and other writers and editors; business contracts with Viking Press and others for her publications and for movie rights; handwritten and typed manuscripts and proofs for her books Dreams of Sleep, Rich in Love, and Fireman's Fair, as well as typescripts of works by other authors (including Robb Forman Dew and Louise Erdrich); reviews of her own work as well as reviews written by Humphreys of others' works; and information detailing her speaking engagements and interviews. In addition, the collection contains clippings of reviews and interviews, photographs and negatives (16 black-and-white, 4 color, and 23 negatives); audiotapes from a "Women in Literature" series in which Humphreys participated; and 10 electronic files of book manuscripts, especially Dreams of Sleep, originally on computer disks and now migrated to the electronic records server. Also included are books inscribed to Humphreys and seven scrapbooks containing additional correspondence regarding her work as well as reviews.
Books -- Reviews; Authors, American -- South Carolina; Women authors -- 20th century; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Correspondence; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Interviews; Clippings (information artifacts); Authors, American -- 20th century -- Southern States; Machine-readable records; Color photographs; Black-and-white photographs; Audiotapes; Scrapbooks; Negatives (photographic); Humphreys, Josephine; Dew, Robb Forman; Humphreys, Josephine; Erdrich, Louise
- Accession 92-074
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Correspondence and business contracts in boxes 1 and 2 are restricted.
  - Correspondence and Miscellanous, (1983-1993); Speaking Engagements, (1988-1989) (Box 1)
    Correspondence and business contracts are restricted.
    - Rural Seminar-Expectations and Evaluations [note: the folder appears to contain correspondence, 1992] (Box 1)
    - Correspondence and souvenirs, 1983-1991, 19 folders (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      Includes letter from Mrs. Onassis, 1988; telegram from Harriet Wasserman; and Yale Memo Book, 1968.
    - [Review in] Spy! (Box 1)
    - Travel notes, 1986-"Notes written while driving through the South" (Box 1)
    - Poetry Center 92nd St., 1990 April 8 (Box 1)
    - PEN-Hemingway Prize-Judge, 1990 January-May (newspaper clippings) (Box 1)
    - Student Comments R[ich] I[n] L[ove] (Box 1)
    - Movie script [ Rich In Love screenplay by Alfred Uhry], 1991 (Box 1)
    - Story for George Garrett, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Prince of Wales [Business Forum address to spouses], 1990 (Box 1)
    - Printed Material, 1991-1993, 5 folders, including one legal in oversize box (Box 1)
    - Speaking engagements and workshops, 1988-1989, 19 folders (Box 1)
  - Travel, Contracts, Articles about Humphreys, (1984-1991) (Box 2)
    - Travel, 1988-1989, 9 folders (Box 2)
    - Calendars and travel schedules, 1986-1988, 6 folders (Box 2)
    - Contracts and Business, Photos, Catalogs, Souvenirs, 1987-1988, 48 folders, including one legal size in oversize box; newspaper clippings (Box 2)
      Includes movie and publishing contracts, correspondence with various presses, and book covers for Rich in Love.
    - Articles and interviews about Humphreys, 1984-1991, 7 folders; newspaper clippings (Box 2)
  - Articles and Interviews about Humphreys, (1984-1991)(cont.); Reviews, articles, and interviews by Humphreys, (1988-1996); Reviews of Humphreys' work, (1984-1991) (Box 3)
    - Articles and interviews about Humphreys, 1984-1990, 4 folders; newspaper clippings (Box 3)
    - Reviews by Humphreys, 1988-1990, 14 folders (Box 3)
    - Articles by Humphreys, 1988-1996, 21 folders, including one legal in oversize box (Box 3)
    - Reviews of Humphreys' work, Rich in Love, Dreams of Sleep, Fireman's Fair, and A World Unsuspected, 1984-1991, 14 folders (Box 3)
      Includes thesis by John Richard Woodmanse on Humphreys' work.
    - Reviews for Rich in Love, Dreams of Sleep, Fireman's Fair, and A World Unsuspected, 1984-1991 (cont.), 14 folders (Box 4)
  - First Draft Manuscripts- Dreams of Sleep, 1978-1982 (Box 5)
  - Manuscripts- Dreams of Sleep and Rich in Love, 1982-1985, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Manuscripts- Rich in Love, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts- Fireman's Fair, 1989-1990 (Box 8)
  - Manuscripts- Fireman's Fair, 1989-1990 (Box 9)
  - Manuscripts- Fireman's Fair, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
  - Manuscripts- Rich in Love, 1987 (Box 11)
  - Manuscripts- Rich in Love, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Subject Files: Southern States Tour and Hurricane Hugo, 1987 (Box 13)
- Accessions 92-101, 96-098
  - Typescripts and Manuscripts (1978?-1986 and undated) (Box 1)
    - Dreams of Sleep typescripts, 3 folders (Box 1)
      2nd typescript for Viking, 1983 April 1
    - Dreams of Sleep with editing marks by Reynolds Price, 1982 November, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - The Time of Her Life (typescript) by Robb Forman Dew, undated, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous handwritten copy, 1986 and undated (Box 1)
    - For A World Unsuspected (edited typescript), undated (Box 1)
    - Earliest precursor of Rich in Love, c. 1983 (Box 1)
    - Electronic files on Disk 004 were originally filed here. (Box 1)
    - Dreams of Sleep, chapter 1, undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Anna Tyson, Chapter One: Grandmother's House, by Robb Forman Dew, c. 1986 (Box 1)
    - These are copies of the 50 pages of Dreams of Sleep I sent to R. Price in 1982, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Earliest tries at Dreams of Sleep, c. 1978? (Box 1)
    - Original typescript for Dreams of Sleep, undated, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - The Beet Queen (typescript), by Louise Erdrich, 1986, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Dreams of Sleep, unrevised and unpublished proofs, undated (Box 1)
    - Rich in Love, unrevised and unpublished proofs, undated (Box 1)
  - Books inscribed to JH, Yearbooks, Clippings, Audiotapes, Reviews, Photographs (1960-1987 and undated) (Box 2)
    - Books inscribed to JH
      - A Generous Man, by Reynolds Price (Box 2)
      - Love and Work, by Reynolds Price (Box 2)
      - Edisto, by Padgett Powell (Box 2)
      - The Beet Queen, by Louise Erdrich (Box 2)
      - A Duke miscellany: Narrative and verse of the sixties, ed. by William Blackburn (Box 2)
    - The Spiral [Ashley Hall, Charleston, SC, yearbook], 1960, 1962, 1963, 1964, 4 volumes (Box 2)
    - Clippings, 1983-1987, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987 and undated (Box 2)
    - Souvenirs, 1963-1967, 1980-1987, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Interviews, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
    - Photographs, 1960s-1980s (Box 2)
    - Magazine reviews of Dreams of Sleep, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Audiotapes:
      - Long Beach, CA, "Women in Literature", date: 1985-1986?:
        - #2 Sharon Kay Penman (Box 2)
        - #3 Audrey Peterson (Box 2)
        - #4 Nancy Reeves (Box 2)
        - #5 Maryse Conde (Box 2)
        - #6 Josephine Humphreys (Box 2)
        - #7 Dottie Lamm (Box 2)
      - Loneliness, by Renny Scott, undated (Box 2)
  - Letters, Reviews of other books, Miscellaneous ( 1946, 1967-1987) (Box 3)
    - Resume, c. 1972 (Box 3)
    - Bought from Colonial Antiques--Mr. Schwerin. Re: Dawn Langley Hall Simmons and 56 Society Street, undated (Box 3)
    - Maps (Box 3)
    - Reviews of other books, 1985 and undated (Box 3)
    - W. G. Clark drawings (Box 3)
    - Letters, 1946, 1967-1987, 6 folders (Box 3)
    - The Orlando Sentinel [newspaper] promotional packet, 1986 (Box 3)
    - American Booksellers Association Convention and Trade Exhibit guide, New Orleans, 1986 May 24-27 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbooks (1982-1986) (Box 4-5)
  - Clippings (3 folders) (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Calendar (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Interviews (Oversize-folder 1)